A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Resources and the Environment, Program Staff Files FA641
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Resources and the Environment, Program Staff Files
1963-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA641
4.8 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Arrangement
Arranged into 3 series: I. Subject Files. II. Resource and Environment Diary. III. Chronological Correspondence Files.
Ford Foundation
- Subject Files, 1963-1980; I
  - Resources and Environment Study" -- Discussion Paper, Dec 1963 (Box 1)
  - Resources and Environment Study -- Final Report and Recommendations, Apr 1964 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Natural Resources -- Discussion Papers (1/2), Feb 27-Mar 1, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Natural Resources -- Discussion Papers (2/2) (second copy), Feb 27-Mar 1, 1964 (Box 1)
  - "Land Acquisition" -- Discussion Paper, Dec 1964 (Box 1)
  - "Critical Needs in Land Use and Preservation: A Suggested Role for the Ford Foundation" -- Report of Advisory Committee on Land Use and Preservation, Sep 15, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Response to Environmental and Resource Problems -- Report of the Seminar on the Uses of Ecology (Ford Foundation), Jan 26-27, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Conservation Foundation, Inc. -- Committee for Economic Development -- RGA, Press Release, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Energy Grants, Fiscal Years 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Energy Grants -- RFF; Environmental Action Foundation; Rand Corporation; Brookings Institution, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Environmental Defense Fund, Inc. -- RGAs, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation -- Personnel Policies -- Travel and Expenses Handbook, 1977 (Box 1)
  - India Trip File -- Energy Related Materials, 1979 (Box 1)
  - "Energy: The Next Twenty Years" -- Study Group Members and Energy Report and Reviews, 1978 (Box 1)
  - "Energy: The Next Twenty Years", 1979 (Box 1)
  - Energy Books -- Reviews of "Energy: The Next Twenty Years"; "Energy in America's Future"; "Energy Future", 1980 (Box 1)
  - Energy Consultants Meeting File (incl. May 13, 1980 meeting) (Box 1)
  - (The) Energy Policy Project, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Gravel, Mike (Alaska senator) -- Government Stock Ownership Corporation (GSOC), 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Nuclear Energy Policy Study Group -- Members, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Nuclear Energy Policy Study -- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Program Plans, Energy Studies Grants, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Consultant -- Gordon Harrison, Oct 1, 1978-Apr 15, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Consultant -- Gordon Harrison -- General Correspondence Re: Workshops, Papers, etc., 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Consultant -- Vernon W. Ruttan, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Resources for the Future -- Re: Energy Projects (including ARDEN), 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Resources for the Future -- Ford Foundation Grant, 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Saving Energy: An Idea for a Private-Sector Initiative" by M. Sviridoff, 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Science in this Foundation" Memo by Marshall Robinson and Related Science Memoranda, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (SIPI) -- Meetings and Conferences, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Shareholders Resolution -- Pacific Gas and Electric Co., 1980 (Box 2)
  - Staff -- Memoranda (to and from) Re: Ford Foundation Administrative Policies, Staff Appointments, etc., 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - State Environmental Management Program, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Status Reports -- Education and Public Policy Division (grants lists), 1980 (Box 2)
  - Thomas, Franklin A. -- Memos Re: Various Subjects Incl. Resources and the Environment and Education and Public Policy Grants, Proposals, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Trustee Committee Paper -- Resources and the Environment Program, Dec 1979 (Box 2)
  - UNESCO MINESPOL II Conference (Belgrade, Yugoslavia), Sep 11-16, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Urban Impact Statements, n.d. (Box 2)
- Resource and Environment Diary, 1967-1974; II
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, Feb 1967-Dec 1968 (Box 2)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, Jan 1969-Dec 1971 (Box 2)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, Jan 1972-Nov 1973 (Box 2)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Diary of Activities, Jan-Apr 1974 (Box 2)
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1963-1973; III
  - Gordon Harrison -- Chronological Correspondence, Apr-Dec 1963 (Box 3)
  - Gordon Harrison -- Chronological Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Jun 1965 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1965 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Jun 1966 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1966 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Mar 1967 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1967 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, May-Jun 1967 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jul-Aug 1970 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Sep-Dec 1970 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1971 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, May 1971 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1971 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1971 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Sep-Oct 1971 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Nov-Dec 1971 (Box 3)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jan 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Feb 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Mar 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, May 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jul 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Oct 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Nov 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Dec 1972 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jan 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Feb 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Mar 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, May 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Jul 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Oct 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Nov 1973 (Box 4)
  - Resources and the Environment -- Chronological Correspondence, Dec 1973 (Box 4)
- Appendix A: Reports
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell; Saving Energy -- An Idea for a Private-Sector Initiative, n.d. (Report #019927)
  - National Economic Research Associates; Energy: The Next Twenty Years, n.d. (Report #019928)